Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson about going to the
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节中级课程，主题是去
bank.
银行。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to go to the bank and we need to do something there.
今天我们要去银行，而且需要在那里办点事。
We're not going to put money in the bank actually.
实际上，我们不是去存钱。
We're going to make a transfer.
我们要办理转账。
Okay, so you'll learn all about this in a minute.
好的，你马上就会了解这一切。
Let's take a listen to the dialogue first.
我们先来听一下对话。
Good morning.
早上好。
Welcome to Bank of the USA.
欢迎来到美国银行。
How may I help you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
Hi, I need to transfer some money to another account.
你好，我需要转一些钱到另一个账户。
It's urgent.
很紧急。
Okay.
好的。
Have you made a wire transfer at our bank before?
您以前在我们银行办理过电汇吗？
No, I've never made a transfer before.
没有，我以前从未办理过转账。
It's all right.
没关系。
I will take you through the procedure.
我会带您走完整个流程。
Are you transferring funds to a company or an individual account?
您是要转账给公司账户还是个人账户？
A company account.
公司账户。
I need to pay a bill.
我需要付一笔账单。
Okay.
好的。
I'll need the name of the company and their bank routing number as well as their bank's
我需要公司的名称、他们的银行路由号码，以及他们银行的
address and phone number.
地址和电话号码。
I have all the information in this folder.
所有信息都在这个文件夹里。
Well, you've come prepared.
嗯，您准备得很充分。
I have all the necessary materials so we can go ahead and make the transfer right now.
我所有必需的材料都带齐了，我们现在就可以进行转账。
It's a simple transaction and we can process it today.
这是一笔简单的交易，我们今天就能处理。
Oh, that's such a relief.
哦，那真是太好了。
I didn't want the payment to be overdue.
我不想让这笔付款逾期。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
It's my pleasure.
不客气。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So interesting dialogue, very common situation.
这段对话很有趣，是非常常见的情况。
We need to transfer money to another account.
我们需要把钱转到另一个账户。
So we have some very interesting vocab words right there.
所以这里面有一些很有意思的词汇。
Why don't we take a look at those on Language Takeaway.
我们不如在“语言要点”部分看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So Marco, the first word is one that you've already said a couple of times in today's
那么马可，第一个词是你今天在课程中已经说过几次的。
lesson.
课程。
It is to transfer.
就是“转账”。
Okay, that's right.
没错，就是这样。
We need to transfer money.
我们需要转账。
So to transfer, what does this verb mean?
那么“转账”这个动词是什么意思呢？
So to transfer means to move from one place to another.
“转账”的意思是从一个地方移动到另一个地方。
In the case of money, you're moving money from one bank to another bank or from one
在钱的情况下，就是把钱从一个银行移动到另一个银行，或者从一个
account to another account.
账户移动到另一个账户。
So just think of transferring as moving.
所以就把“转账”想象成“移动”就行了。
That's right.
没错。
But the bank teller also mentioned something about a wire transfer.
但银行柜员还提到了“电汇”。
So that's basically the same thing, right?
那基本上是一回事，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So when you're talking about money, you don't actually take a bag of money and you don't
所以当谈到钱时，你实际上不会拿着一袋钱
walk to another bank to put it in the account.
走到另一家银行去存进账户。
A wire transfer means that the transfer is electronic.
“电汇”意味着转账是电子的。
One bank tells another bank that you're going to exchange this money.
一家银行告诉另一家银行你要交换这笔钱。
So it's going to move from one person to another person or from one company to another company.
所以它会从一个人转移到另一个人，或者从一家公司转移到另一家公司。
But it's never actually the money itself.
但实际的钱本身从未移动过。
It's always just the number of funds in the account.
账户里的资金数量总是关键。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a wire transfer, to transfer money electronically from one account to another.
好的，电汇就是通过电子方式将资金从一个账户转移到另一个账户。
And talking about this word account, we're talking about a bank account.
说到“账户”这个词，我们指的是银行账户。
What is this?
这是什么？
Well, this is really important even if you're not making a wire transfer or if you're not
嗯，这真的很重要，即使你不进行电汇或者不在银行工作。
working at a bank.
即使不在银行工作。
This is something that most people have for their personal use.
这是大多数人个人使用的东西。
So an account is a space for money in a bank that's kind of registered to one person or
所以，账户是银行里一个存放资金的空间，通常登记在一个人或一家公司名下。
one company.
或者一家公司名下。
And there are many, many different kinds of accounts.
而且有很多很多不同类型的账户。
That's right.
没错。
Many of you probably have a savings account.
你们很多人可能都有一个储蓄账户。
This is where you keep your money to save for the future.
这是你存钱以备未来之需的地方。
Or many companies or people have a checking account or a default account where basically
或者很多公司或个人有一个支票账户或默认账户，基本上你往里面存钱，
you put money in, but you're also taking money out and paying for bills and paying to go
同时也会取钱来支付账单、看电影等。
to the movies, etc.
等等。
Yeah, so these different accounts have different rules.
是的，这些不同的账户有不同的规则。
They have rules about how much money you can keep in them or how much money you need to
它们有关于你能存多少钱或需要多少钱才能开户的规则。
open them.
才能开户。
So the basic word here is account.
所以这里的基本词是 account。
And just remember that companies and people can all have accounts at a bank.
记住，公司和人都可以在银行拥有账户。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so when talking about an account, we're talking about transferring money to another
好的，所以当我们谈论账户时，我们是在说将钱转移到另一个
account.
账户。
We don't say we want to transfer money.
我们不会说“转移钱”。
We say we want to transfer funds.
我们说“转移资金”。
Funds.
资金。
So funds, we usually say in the plural, funds, with an S. This means money.
所以 funds，我们通常用复数形式，funds，加 S。这表示钱。
So we're talking about transferring funds from one company to another or I could say
所以我们说的是将资金从一家公司转移到另一家，或者我可以说
I need to deposit funds in my account.
我需要往我的账户里存入资金。
That's right.
没错。
Now an interesting word because funds with an S at the end, that's a plural noun as you
现在一个有趣的词是 funds，末尾加 S，这是一个复数名词，正如你
said, but if we use it in the singular, it could also be a verb, to fund.
所说，但如果用单数形式，它也可以是一个动词，to fund。
That's right.
没错。
And that means to pay for something or someone.
意思是支付某物或某人的费用。
So my grandfather funded my college education.
所以我的祖父资助了我的大学教育。
He paid money for my college education.
他支付了我大学教育的费用。
That's right.
没错。
So both words, either the verb or the noun, have to do with money.
所以这两个词，无论是动词还是名词，都与钱有关。
And when we're talking about transferring money, we're talking about a type of transaction,
当我们谈论转移钱时，我们是在说一种交易，
right?
对吧？
Where a bank transfer or a wire transfer is a type of transaction.
银行转账或电汇是一种交易类型。
That's right.
没错。
So a transaction is a noun and it's something that you do at a bank, for example, usually
所以 transaction 是一个名词，是你在银行做的事情，例如，通常
involving the exchange of money.
涉及金钱交换。
So a wire transfer is a kind of transaction, but also depositing or putting money into
所以电汇是一种交易，但存入或把钱放进
my savings account is also a kind of transaction.
我的储蓄账户也是一种交易。
That's right.
没错。
So a transaction is kind of like a business move or a business deal involving money.
所以 transaction 有点像一种商业动作或涉及金钱的商业交易。
For example, a transaction can also be buying a car.
例如，交易也可以是买车。
That's right.
没错。
So the transaction is I give my money to Marco, the car salesperson, and the transaction is
所以交易是我把钱给 Marco，汽车销售员，交易是
exchanging that money for the car.
用钱交换那辆车。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And lastly, since we needed to pay a bill, we were worried that the bill will be overdue
最后，因为我们需要付账单，我们担心账单会逾期，
and that's why we really needed to make this wire transfer.
这就是为什么我们真的需要做这笔电汇。
Okay.
好的。
So to be overdue is to be late.
所以 overdue 意思是迟了。
So think about due.
想想 due。
This is the time when something has to be done by.
这是某件事必须完成的截止时间。
So for example, if the bill for the electricity is due on Wednesday, but I pay it on Thursday,
例如，如果电费账单在星期三到期，但我星期四才付，
it's overdue.
它就逾期了。
Okay.
好的。
So it not only has to do with money, it could also be something that is late.
所以它不仅与钱有关，也可以指某件事迟了。
For example, if I visit my grandma after not going there for three months, you would say
例如，如果我三个月没去看奶奶，然后去看她，你会说
this visit is long overdue.
这次拜访早就该做了。
That means Marco should have visited his grandmother earlier, but he didn't.
意思是 Marco 应该早点去看他奶奶，但他没去。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great vocab there all involving banks and different types of words you may
所以这里有很多很棒的词汇，都与银行有关，以及你在
find when transferring funds.
转账资金时可能遇到的不同类型的词。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
那我们再听一遍对话，稍后回来进行流利度训练。
Good morning.
早上好。
Welcome to Bank of the USA.
欢迎来到美国银行。
How may I help you today?
今天我能为您做什么？
Hi.
你好。
I'm here to transfer some money to another account.
我来这里是为了转一些钱到另一个账户。
It's urgent.
很紧急。
Okay.
好的。
Have you made a wire transfer at our bank before?
您以前在我们银行做过电汇吗？
No, I've never made a transfer before.
没有，我以前从未做过转账。
It's all right.
没关系。
I will take you through the procedure.
我会带您走完整个流程。
Are you transferring funds to a company or an individual account?
您是要转账给公司还是个人账户？
A company account.
公司账户。
I need to pay a bill.
我需要付一笔账单。
Okay.
好的。
I'll need the name of the company and their bank routing number, as well as their bank's
我需要公司名称和他们的银行路由号码，以及他们银行的
address and phone number.
地址和电话号码。
I have all the information in this folder.
所有信息都在这个文件夹里。
Well, you've come prepared.
嗯，您准备得很充分。
I have all the necessary materials so we can go ahead and make the transfer right now.
我有所有必要的材料，所以我们现在就可以进行转账。
It's a simple transaction and we can process it today.
这是一个简单的交易，我们今天就能处理。
Oh, that's such a relief.
哦，那真是松了一口气。
I didn't want the payment to be overdue.
我不想付款逾期。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
It's my pleasure.
这是我的荣幸。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So we have three key phrases for you.
所以我们为你准备了三个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在 Fluency Builder 中看看这些内容。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So our first phrase comes from something that the person at the bank told the client.
我们的第一个短语来自银行工作人员对客户说的一句话。
That person said, it's all right.
那个人说，没关系。
I will take you through the procedure.
我会带你走一遍流程。
Okay.
好的。
So let's look at this word procedure.
我们来看看“procedure”这个词。
Procedure can be many different things, but what is it in this case?
程序可以指很多不同的东西，但在这个案例中它指的是什么呢？
It's basically the steps or the process of taking money from the account and transferring
这基本上就是从账户中取钱并转账的步骤或过程。
it to another one.
把它转到另一个上面。
That's the procedure.
这是标准流程。
So we have to do all the steps, you have to fill out the paperwork, you have to sign here
所以我们必须完成所有步骤，你得填好文件，在这里签字。
and all these things.
以及所有这些事情。
Right.
好的。
So we're talking about a wire transfer.
所以我们来谈谈电汇。
So there is a procedure for doing a wire transfer.
所以电汇是有流程的。
That means like you say, there are steps that we have to go through to complete this action.
就像你说的，要完成这个动作，我们需要经过一些步骤。
But we can also have a medical procedure.
但我们也可以进行医疗程序。
So a heart surgery has its own procedure, but that's very different from a wire transfer
所以心脏手术有自己的流程，但这和电汇的流程很不一样。
procedure.
流程。
That's right.
没错。
But it's still, it has different steps and different things that you must do in order
但它仍然有不同步骤和必须按顺序做的事情。
to operate.
才能操作。
But when we have a bank teller who will take us through the procedure, this means that
但当我们有银行柜员带我们走流程时，这意味着他或她会帮我们理解需要完成的步骤。
he or she will help us understand the steps we need to complete.
他或她会帮我们理解需要完成的步骤。
That's right.
没错。
So this, we could also use this in another bank scenario if maybe my little brother wants
所以这个用法也可以用在另一个银行场景中，比如我弟弟想开个银行账户。
to open a bank account.
想开个银行账户。
So I'm going to take him through the procedure of what he needs.
所以我会带他走一遍需要准备的东西的流程。
He needs to maybe get a copy of his ID.
他可能需要复印身份证。
He needs to have $20, etc.
他需要有20美元等等。
Take him through the procedure.
带他走流程。
So you're going to help him.
所以你要帮他。
All right.
好的。
That's right.
没错。
So this is something we say about why the person is so anxious to transfer this money.
所以这是我们用来解释为什么这个人这么着急要转账的说法。
The person says, I have a company account.
这个人说，我有一个公司账户。
I need to pay a bill.
我需要付一笔账单。
So this is why the money is going to be transferred from one place to another to pay the bill.
所以这就是为什么钱要从一个地方转到另一个地方来支付账单。
So this is something we say not just about, you know, company things or business things.
所以这不仅仅适用于公司或商业事务。
We say about our things at home, like the electricity bill.
我们也用它来说家里的事，比如电费账单。
That's right.
没错。
And actually this is more and more common.
实际上，这种情况越来越普遍了。
We pay our bills using our electronic banking services.
我们用电子银行服务来支付账单。
So for example, maybe he needs to pay the electricity bill or the telephone bill and
比如，他可能需要支付电费或电话费，
this is why we're transferring money.
这就是我们转账的原因。
So to pay a bill is to cancel the bill.
所以“付账单”就是结清账单。
That's right.
没错。
So I could say, it's time to pay the bills.
所以我可以这样说：该付账单了。
It's the end of the month.
月底了。
Or, oh shoot, I forgot to pay the bills again.
或者：哦，糟了，我又忘了付账单。
They're going to turn my electricity off.
他们要把我的电给断了。
That's right.
没错。
And now an interesting phrase here, very specific to making transfers.
这里有一个有趣的短语，专门用于转账。
When we talk about bank routing number, a bank routing number.
当我们说到银行路由号码时，银行路由号码。
Well this is pretty simple actually.
其实这很简单。
If you're going to transfer money, you need to be able to tell the bank where the money
如果你要转账，你需要告诉银行钱
will go.
会去哪里。
So you can't just say Mr. Smith.
所以你不能只说史密斯先生。
You have to have a number for the account and each number is unique.
你必须有一个账户号码，而且每个号码都是唯一的。
It's special and it's usually very, very long.
它是特殊的，而且通常非常非常长。
That's right.
没错。
And actually it also has to do with what bank it is because obviously you can't just say,
实际上，这也跟是哪家银行有关，因为显然你不能只说，
oh, Bank of USA because, you know, maybe there are two banks with the same name or maybe
哦，美国银行，因为你知道，可能有两家同名的银行，或者也许
there's one Bank of USA in the United States and there's another one in, I don't know,
美国有一家美国银行，而另一家在，我不知道，
in Europe.
在欧洲。
Right.
对。
So you have to have a certain number or letter combination in the bank routing number.
所以你必须有一个特定的数字或字母组合作为银行路由号码。
And so the kind of account, is it savings or is it a business account and so on and
还有账户类型，是储蓄账户还是商业账户等等，
so forth so that you know exactly where the money will go because you don't want to give
这样你就能确切知道钱会去哪里，因为你不想把钱
the money to the wrong person.
给错人。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great things on this lesson.
这节课有很多很棒的内容。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for one last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Good morning.
早上好。
Welcome to Bank of the USA.
欢迎来到美国银行。
How may I help you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
Hi, I need to transfer some money to another account.
嗨，我需要转一些钱到另一个账户。
It's urgent.
这很紧急。
Okay.
好的。
Have you made a wire transfer at our bank before?
你以前在我们银行做过电汇吗？
No, I've never made a transfer before.
没有，我以前从来没转过账。
It's all right.
没关系。
I will take you through the procedure.
我会带你走一遍流程。
Are you transferring funds to a company or an individual account?
你是要把钱转到公司账户还是个人账户？
A company account.
公司账户。
I need to pay a bill.
我需要付一笔账单。
Okay.
好的。
I'll need the name of the company and their bank routing number as well as their bank's
我需要公司的名称、他们的银行路由号码，以及他们银行的
address and phone number.
地址和电话号码。
I have all the information in this folder.
我所有信息都在这个文件夹里。
Well, you've come prepared.
嗯，你准备得很充分。
I have all the necessary materials so we can go ahead and make the transfer right now.
我所有必需的材料都带齐了，所以我们现在就可以进行转账。
It's a simple transaction and we can process it today.
这是一笔简单的交易，我们今天就能处理。
Oh, that's such a relief.
哦，那真是太好了。
I didn't want the payment to be overdue.
我不想让付款逾期。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢你。
It's my pleasure.
不客气。
So Marco, this is really, really important stuff.
所以马可，这真的是非常重要的事情。
Even if you're not talking about the business context, but you're trying to make transactions
即使你不是在谈商业场景，而是想为个人生活进行交易，
for your personal life.
也是如此。
That's right.
没错。
Just imagine maybe you're abroad, you're in the United States and maybe your parents need
想象一下，也许你在国外，在美国，而你父母需要
to send you money.
给你寄钱。
So maybe you need to go to the bank and receive those funds.
所以你可能需要去银行接收那些资金。
So now you have the language and the vocab necessary to more or less talk about a bank
现在你有了必要的语言和词汇，可以大致谈论银行
transfer.
转账了。
You can say, I was wired money from Spain, for example.
比如你可以说，我从西班牙收到了电汇。
Right.
对。
And one of the most famous places to do this that you'll find all over the United States
而全美国最常见的一个办理这种业务的地方
is Western Union.
就是西联汇款。
That's right.
没错。
You can go to them and say, I need to transfer money or I need to transfer funds.
你可以去那里说，我需要转账或我需要汇款。
And so they will send the money from one Western Union to another Western Union.
然后他们会把钱从一个西联汇款点送到另一个西联汇款点。
And then the person at home or wherever will pick up your money.
然后在家或其他地方的人就能取到你的钱。
And so they will wire the money from one place to another.
所以他们把钱从一个地方电汇到另一个地方。
That's right.
没错。
And I think this is how it started.
而且我觉得这就是它最初的样子。
The wire transferring was, I don't think it was originally with banks.
电汇，我认为最初并不是银行开始的。
I think it was something, some sort of service similar to Western Union or maybe Western
我觉得它是一些类似西联汇款的服务，或者可能就是西联
Union started it.
汇款发起的。
You mean it was like telegraphs?
你是说它像电报一样？
Yeah, something like this.
嗯，差不多吧。
But I don't know if it was from bank to bank.
但我不确定是不是银行之间开始的。
It's an interesting story though.
不过这是个有趣的故事。
We'll have to look it up and let you know.
我们得查一下，然后告诉你。
I'm not sure of the story either.
我也不太清楚这个故事。
But if you're out there and you need to wire some money now you know how to do it.
但如果你在外面需要电汇钱，现在你知道怎么做了。
Well, not how to do it, but you have to talk about it.
嗯，不是怎么做，而是你会谈论它了。
We hope you have luck with this.
我们希望你能顺利办成。
And if you have any questions, you know where to find us, EnglishPod.com.
如果你有任何问题，你知道在哪里能找到我们，EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。
Electric vientarelli Carvis only from El Cdito cheap on MailTV and Piece mascara